When talking about Gadhafi, we are going to talk about the adjacency matrix, what is adjacency matrix
graphs are commonly presented in two ways.
The adjacency metrics and adjacency list you can't like always drew a graph for a computer.
We need to supply it with adjacency matrix or adjacency list.
For that, we are going to understand and learn the two adjacency matrix representation and the list.
An adjacency metrics, is it to the array of Vertex Time Vertex V Times V vertices?
Each row and column represent a vertex.
If the value of any element at a I and J is one, its represent that there is an edge connecting a vertex
and vertex J.
I know you didn't.
You may be a sometimes confusing.
Let's take an example.
Zero, one, two and three.
We have connection between zero and one zero one two zero and three and one and two.
This is an undirected graph and lets you present it in form of adjacency matrix.
This is a matrix, and we start by.
Zero.
From from here, from the left, this column, Andrew, we we read from this site, from the columns
to the arrows.
OK, now let's see the first example.
Zero is connected to one two.
And the city and zero does not.
It is not connected to itself.
It's not making air for air flash indicating itself like this.
So if you have a flash here that indicates aircraft, it is connected to itself, so it would be connected
zero with zero.
But in this case, we are not having only that connection.
Zero one zero two and zero three.
We start from here from this first position, and we said that it is the first zero.
And we put the vertices also zero, one, two and three zero is connected with zero, no.
So we've put Z here.
We are studying zero.
OK.
I repeat, we are studying here.
Zero.
OK now.
Zero connected with zero, no.
So we put zero zero is connected with one.
Yes.
So we've put one zero connected with two.
So we put one.
Zero is connected with three.
Yes.
So we put.
Let's move to another one.
Another note one is connected with.
Zero.
Yes.
So we put one one is connected.
Let me put here another.
Colored.
One is connected with zero, yes.
One is connected with one.
No, there is no flash indicating it's it's connected itself, so it puts you.
Zero one is connected with two.
Yes.
So we put one.
OK.
One is connected with three.
No.
So we put here zero.
OK.
Let me continue.
Let's move to the third element, which is due to hear two is connected with zero.
Yes.
Two is connected with one.
Two is connected with two.
No two is connected with three.
No.
So one one zero two.
Let's move to the third.
The the last note three is connected to zero.
Yes.
Syria is connected to one to two to three, no.
So we both see it.
This is the adjacency matrix.
Adjacency matrix pros, the basic operations like adding an edge, removing an edge and checking whether
there is edge from Vertex III to Vertex are extremely time efficient.
Constant time operations constant time operation means of one.
If the graph is dense and the number of edges is large, the adjacency matrix should be the first choice.
Even if that graph and the adjacency matrix is sparse, we can present it using data structure for sparse
matrices.
The biggest advantages over there for any representation, however, comes from the use of matrices.
The recent advantage fences in the hardware enables us to perform even expensive matrix operations on
the chip you.
By performing operations on the adjacent metrics, we can get important insights into the nature of
the graph and the relationship between its vertices.
Adjacency metrics Cons The V times vs space requirements for adjacency metrics make it memory hug graphs
out in the wild usually don't have too many connections, and this is the major reason why adjacency
lists are the better choice of for the most desk that we are going to learn and the next videos.
So while basic operations are easy, operations like in edge and out edge edges are expensive when using
the adjacency matrix representation.
Let's see the applications of adjacency matrix creating, routing table in network and navigation tasks.
So we use the adjacency matrix in the routing tables in the network and the navigation tasks.
In the next video, we are going to learn how to implement the adjacency metrics in C and later on in
the next.